#大家好 今天去挖點攝影小哥家的紅薯
Hi everyone! Today we're picking the red potatoes at Mr. Cameraman's place.
#他家紅薯現在熟了哦
His red potatoes are now ready.
#就在前面一點
They're over there.
#你看 終於到了這個地瓜地裡面
Look! Finally we arrive at the potatoes field.
#這個 紅薯苗啊
These, potato leaves,
#可以用來餵小豬哦
can be used to feed the piglet.
#小豬很喜歡吃的 這個
The piglet likes them a lot, the leaves.
#你看 攝影小哥的女兒
Look! Mr. Cameraman's daughter,
#攝影小哥的媽媽
Mr. Cameraman's mom
#都過來啦
are here too.
#她知道我這 我們在這裡 拔這個
She knows that we're, we're here to pick the,
#拔這個
pick the,
#這個 這個 這個 紅薯葉
the, the, the, potato leaves,
#給小豬吃
for the piglet.
#會不會拔 胡韋汝
Do you know how to pick? Hu Weiru
#你會不會拔
Do you know?
#我拔不出來
I can't pick it out.
#拔不出來呀
Can't pick it out?
#你喜不喜歡吹地瓜
Do you like potatoes?
#我又不喜歡吃
No, that's not my favourite.
#喜歡吃是不是
You like it, don't you?
#喜歡吃就多挖一點回去哦
Then we need to pick more.
#等一下我幫你挖一點啊
I can help you.
#給不給 給不給我家那個劉星辰吃
Could, could my son, my son Liu Xingchen also have some?
#給不給
Could he?
#這是你家的 你家的那個地姂地喲
Here is yours, I mean the potato field at your place.
#嗯 我拔不出來
Um....I can't pick them out.
#我幫你呀
Let me help you.
#是不是
See?
#你看 你看 還有花的哦
Look! Look! There're even flowers!
#看到沒有
Can you see the flowers?
#是不是
See?
#放在那裡
Put it over there.
#那麼多啦
I think we have enough.
#這個葉子
The leaves are
#小豬
enough
#小豬能夠吃一頓啦
enough for a meal for the piglet.
#我先挖一點紅薯啊
I gonna pick some red potatoes first.
#挖紅薯才是
The main purpose of coming,
#才是我真正來這裡的
coming here today is nothing but,
#來這裡的目的
but the red potatoes.
#這個土 太硬啦 這個土
The soil is too hard, the soil.
#等下不要挖爛啦
Don't damage it.
#看著來
I need to be very careful.
#奶奶 身上有蟲子
Grandma! There's a bug on you.
#哎呀 有哦
Aiyo! I see them!
#挖了一個
Here is one.
#剛好有一個筐
Just so happens that there's a basket.
#看到你就撿啊
Pick whenever you see any, OK?
#嗯
Um.
#有沒有
Any?
#有一個是不是
There's one, right?
#哇 這裡有
Wa! Here're more.
#快點撿
Come on! Pick them up!
#還有 這裡還有
More, there're still more.
#你看 這裡有那麼多
Look! Here're so many!
#快點 你來拿回去
Come on! Put them into the basket.
#誒 還有一個 還有一個大的
Eh! Here's one, a big one.
#大的還是那麼多 (註︰其實這句不太明白，不知她想說「大的還才有那麼大」還是「大的還有很多」)
There're so many big ones.
#小的 壞掉啦
The small one. It's rotten.
#這裡有一個
Here's another one.
Here's one.
#怎麼裡面還有一個
Why is there one more inside?
#都裝不下啦
It's already full.
#爸爸
Daddy
#就挖了那麼一點點
We've picked just a bit here.
#回去啦
Let's go!
#是不是你來提 胡韋汝
Are you carrying it? Hu Weiru
#我又不來提 好重
I can't! It's too heavy.
#那你背鋤頭哦
Then you take the hoe.
#不背 不背
No, no!
#為甚麼不背
Why not?
#真的不背
Really no!
#煮那麼一點點就夠啦
We're cooking just a little bit here,
#別煮那麼多
not too many.
#好 這樣煮
Alright! Just cook it here,
#煮個40分鐘就夠啦
for 40 minutes. It should be fine then.
#哇 全爆開來啦
Wa! All cracked open!
#很香哦 (註︰原字幕沒有，但不加的話難以理解下下句)
Does it smell good?
#嗯 吸了一口蒸氣
Umhm! I can feel it from the steam.
#好香
It smells so good.
#你看 這個
Look! They're
#全裂開啦
all cracked open.
#等一下來
Leave it for a while.
#先把火關掉
Switch it off first.
#等下再吃啦
Let's eat later.
#你看這個番薯 要不要
Have a look at this potato, do you want it?
#要不要吃
Do you want it?
#誒 香不香
Eh! Does it smell good?
#好燙哦
It's very hot.
#這皮都是直接裂開啦
The peal has already cracked open.
#你要不要 紅薯
Do you want it? Red potato
#要不要
Do you?
#好燙哦
It's very hot.
#姐姐
Sis?
Sis
#要不要板栗
Do you want some chestnuts?
#你家的板栗 在那 很好吃的
Your chestnuts. Over there. They're very tasty.
#太燙啦
It's too hot.
#胡說八道
Nonsense!
#我怎麼胡說八道
Why nonsense?
#在她家樹底下撿的是不是
The chestnuts were picked from the trees at her place, right?
#不是 是她家樹上掉的
No! They fell from her trees.
#哦
Oh
#樹上掉的就是
Fell from the trees means,
#也是她家的是不是
from her place, right?
#要不要吃這個 你看 吃這個
Do you want this one? Look! This one.
#我要
Sure!
#很燙哦
It's hot.
#我會一個紙給你包起來吃
Let me wrap it by a tissue paper.
#你要不要
Do you want it?
Do you?
#你也要是不是
You want it, don't you?
#紙紙
Pap pap
#甚麼唧唧
What pap pap?
#紙紙
Pap pap
#哦 還是紙紙包起來 呵呵
Oh! You wanna wrap it by tissue paper? Ho ho
#你那麼會吃 是不是
You know the trick well, don't you?
#妹妹 吃個板栗 (註︰英文好像沒有「妹妹」這類自然的稱呼)
Baby, have a chestnut.
#板栗
Chestnut
#很好吃的 不要哇
It tastes good. You don't want it?
#來 吃一點
Come on! Eat it bit.
#很燙 等一下你把它丟了 燙你手
It's very hot. It'll burn your hand if you drop it.
#現在小孩子 好像比較喜歡吃香的
Now the kids, seem to prefer something with a appealing smell.
#這種地瓜那麼好吃 他們都不喜歡吃
They don't really enjoy this kind potatoes, although they taste that great.
#你看 它的肉 全是紅的
Look! It's all red inside.
#紅啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.